L’Aerophile Collection
Science, Technology, & Business Division, Library of Congress
- Corporations, 1920s-1940s (Boxes 23-44)
  - Abrams, Aera, Aerocessories Simonds, Aerodesign, Air France, Airspeed, Am.Armament, Amiot, Antifuite, Argus, Bleriot, Bloch, Brequet, Brewster, Bronzavia. (Box 23)
    - Avion Amiot. (Envelope 9)
      - “Notice Descriptive & D’Utilisation” submitted to the Ministre De L’Air for the Amiot 370 Hispano-Suiza I2 Y-32 and I2 Y-33. The notebook contains photographs of parts and equipment as well as schematics for each of the aircraft’s parts. (Item 1)
    - Antifuite. (Envelope 10)
      - “Alimentation en Essence” (gasoline supply). (Item 1)
      - Brochure with product descriptions. (Item 2)
    - Argus. (Envelope 11)
      - “Roues et Freins D’Aviation” (wheel brakes) 1938, (2 copies). (Item 1)
      - Advertising pamphlet “Wollen Sie Gewicht Sparen? Dann Verwenden Sie: Argus Flugzeug-Räder Und Bremsen” (They want to save weight? Then they use Argus Flugzeug Radar and Aircraft Brakes) 1938. (Item 2)
      - “Raccords de Tuyauteries Argus” (Argus pipe fittings), 1938, (2 copies). (Item 3)
      - “Flugzeug-Rädar und Bremsen” handbook, 1938. (Item 4)
  - Automotive Products, Beechcraft, Bellanca, Ben Jones, Boeing. (Box 24)
    - Automotive Products Company Ltd. (Envelope 1)
      - Notebook “Lockheed Hydraulic Aircraft Controls” containing diagrams and specifications. (Item 1)
    - Beechcraft Aircraft Corp. (Envelope 2)
      - Beechcraft Model 18 brochure, 1937. (Item 1)
      - Brochure marketed to business executives “Beechcraft: the world’s finest aircraft.” (Item 2)
      - An advertisement depicting Louise Thaden and Blanche Noyes, first women to win the Bendix Trophy (1936). (Item 3)
      - Article “The Sportsmen Test Pilot.” (Item 4)
      - Press release “Test-Pilot President,”, 1939. (Item 5)
      - Information (French) on exporting the Beechcraft C-17R. (Item 6)
      - Beechcraft advertising brochure. (Item 7)
      - Specifications for the C-17B, C-17R and C-17L sent to l’Aérophile. (Item 8)
      - Advertising brochure “More Strength Than You’ll Ever Need.” (Item 9)
      - Specifications for the “Beechcraft model 18 twin motor Transport.” (Item 10)
      - Photograph: model D-17S in flight. (Item 11)
      - Photograph: model D-17R in flight. (Item 12)
      - Photograph: F-17D powered with 330 HP Jacobs engine. (Item 13)
      - Photograph: E-17B powered with 285 H.P Jacobs engine. (Item 14)
      - Photograph: unidentified Beechcraft aircraft. (Item 15)
    - Bellanca Aircraft Corp. (Envelope 3)
      - Press release “fast low-wing Model 28-90 airplanes,” the “World’s fastest commercial type aircraft”, 1937. (Item 1)
      - Press release for the “three-place Ballanca Cruisair”, 1939. (Item 2)
      - Specifications for the “Three-Place Low-Wing Monoplane,” 1939. (Item 3)
      - Advertising brochure “The Bellanca Cruisair.” (Item 4)
      - Press release “Bellanca’s Cruisair,” 1940. (Item 5)
      - Press release “Bellanca Airplanes to be in Chicago for Sportsman’s Show,” 1940. (Item 6)
      - Press release “Bernarr Macfadden – Owner of Bellanca Cruisair Plane.” (Item 7)
    - Bellanca Aircraft Corp. #2. (Envelope 4)
      - Specifications for the 1946 Bellanca Cruisair. (Item 1)
    - Ben Jones, Inc. (Envelope 5)
      - Letter to l’Aérophile containing a detailed description, a diagram and accompanying photographs of the Model S 125. (Item 1)
    - Bennett Aircraft Corp. (Envelope 6)
      - Blueprints for the Bennett Attack Bomber. (Item 1)
    - Blackburn Aircraft Ltd. (Envelope 7)
      - Specifications for the “‘Firebrand’ Mark IV – Centaurus IX Engine.” (Item 1)
      - Three photographs of the F736. (Item 2)
      - Color print depicting the Blackburn Firebrand IV. (Item 3)
      - Two articles reprinted from Flight and The Aeroplane on the Blackburn Firebrand IV. (Item 4)
    - Boeing Airplane Company. (Envelope 8)
      - Press release “Boeing Stratofreighters First (Item 1)
      - Radar-Equipped Production Transports,” 1954.
      - Press release “Macdill Officer First Air Force Pilot to Log 1,000 Hours in B-47,” 1954. (Item 2)
      - Press release “Boeing RB-47E Stratojet,” 1954. (Item 3)
      - Press release “Boeing B-47 Stratojet.” (Item 4)
      - Press release “Photo-Reconnaissance Stratojet in Production at Boeing-Wichita,” 1953. (Item 5)
      - Press release “B-47 Production Marks Noted,” 1953. (Item 6)
      - Press release “Boeing B-47 Production Program Largest in U.S Aviation History,” 1953. (Item 7)
    - Boeing Aircraft Company. (Envelope 9)
      - Press release and five accompanying photographs pertaining to “Passenger Accommodations of Boeing 314 Clipper,” 1938. The release describes the plane as “a ‘Park Avenue suite on wings.’” The photographs include pictures and descriptions of the “Bridal Suite,” recreation room, women’s restroom, sleeping quarters, and seats. (Item 1)
      - Press release for the Boeing “South Seas Clipper.” (Item 2)
      - Press release for the “Model 314 Pan American Clipper.” (Item 3)
      - Specifications for the Boeing 314. (Item 4)
      - Press release introducing the Boeing 314. (Item 5)
      - Press release “the super wind tunnel model” 1940. (Item 6)
      - Specifications for the Boeing 307 Stratoliner. (Item 7)
      - “The Boeing ‘Stratoliner’” by Willy Ley. (Item 8)
      - Letter from Willy Ley to l’Aérophile, 1938. (Item 9)
      - Advance-press release for the Boeing Stratoliner. (Item 10)
      - Press release for the Stratoliner. (Item 11)
      - Specifications and diagram of the Model 247-D Transport. (Item 12)
      - Press release with accompanying specifications and diagram for the Boeing Model 281 Fighter. (Item 13)
      - Specifications for the Model 299 Bomber. (Item 14)
      - Press release for the 299 bomber, 1937. (Item 15)
      - Letter from Boeing Aircraft to l’Aérophile, 1936. (Item 16)
      - Specifications sent to l’Aérophile for the 281 fighter. (Item 17)
      - Specifications sent to l’Aérophile for the 247-D transport. (Item 18)
      - Letter from Boeing Aircraft to l’Aérophile, 1937. (Item 19)
      - Five unidentified photographs of Boeing aircraft including passenger jets and military planes. (Item 20)
      - Press release: B-17 purchase. (Item 21)
      - Press release: B-17 purchase. (Item 22)
      - Press release: delivery of B-17B Flying Fortresses. (Item 23)
      - Press release “Advanced Link Trainer Added to Boeing Equipment,” 1937. (Item 24)
      - Press release “Boeing Model 247-D Transport.” (Item 25)
      - Press release “promotion of Robert J. Minshall ... to the position of vice president and assistant general manager of the Boeing Aircraft Company ... and the appointment of Jay Morrison ... as assistant to the president of the company” 1938. (Item 26)
      - Press release: contract awarded to “The Stearman Aircraft Company.” (Item 27)
      - Press release “Boeing Model 307 Four-Engined Transport.” (Item 28)
      - Press release describing the plant expansion as a result of Allied contracts for “twin-engine attack bombers” 1940. (Item 29)
      - Press release “The appointment of H. Oliver West as special assistant to the president of Boeing Aircraft Company” 1939. (Item 30)
      - Specifications for the Boeing B-17. (Item 31)
      - Press release “newly-completed assembly building.” (Item 32)
      - Photograph of the Boeing 247-D. (Item 33)
      - Photograph of the Boeing B-17 Flying Fortress. (Item 34)
      - Photograph of the YB-17 bomber. (Item 35)
      - Photograph of the 299 bomber. (Item 36)
      - Photograph of the new “assembly building.” (Item 37)
      - Press release: Boeing celebrates seventeen years. (Item 38)
    - Bleriot. (Envelope 10)
      - Bleriot 111 description and specifications. (Item 1)
      - Bleriot 110 description and specifications. (Item 2)
      - Bleriot 125 description and specifications. (Item 3)
      - SPAD 541 description and specifications. (Item 4)
      - Article with specifications for the Bleriot SPAD 922. (Item 5)
      - “Guillemin” J.G.40 description and specifications. (Item 6)
      - Article with specifications for the “Guillemin” J.G 10. (Item 7)
      - Article with specifications for the “Avion Bleriot 137 M 4.” (Item 8)
      - Article with specifications for the Bleriot 127. (Item 9)
      - Article with specifications for the SPAD 91. (Item 10)
      - Two diagrams with specification for Bleriot aircraft. (Item 11)
    - Bloch. (Envelope 11)
      - Specification for the Bloch 220. (Item 1)
      - Letter to l’Aérophile providing notes for various types of aircraft. (Item 2)
      - Four folders describing the 174 RB 3, 162 B 5, I35 B4 and the I5I. (Item 3)
    - Brewster Aeronautical Corp. (Envelope 12)
      - Blueprints to the Brewster bomber and fighter. (Item 1)
    - Breguet. (Envelope 13)
      - Two unidentified photographs of Breguet airplanes. (Item 1)
      - Three diagrams of the Breguet 730. (Item 2)
      - Diagram depicting the dimensions of the “Hydravion Bréguet 730.” (Item 3)
      - Diagram showing dimensions for the Caudron Goéland C.445. (Item 4)
      - Specifications for the “Hydravion Breguet 521 Bizerte.” (Item 5)
      - Brochure for the 470T “Fulgur.” (Item 6)
      - Specifications sent to l’Aérophile for the 462-B4. (Item 7)
      - Specifications sent to l’Aérophile for the 534T. (Item 8)
      - Letter sent to l’Aérophile, 1936. (Item 9)
      - Brochure for the Breguet “Bizerte.” (Item 10)
      - Specifications sent to l’Aérophile for the “Fulgur” 470 T. (Item 11)
      - Description and specifications for the 470T “Fulgur.” (Item 12)
      - Répertoire des Avions, September 1930, featuring the Breguet Biplane Type 27 A2. (Item 13)
      - Diagram showing dimensions for an unidentified airplane. (Item 14)
      - Descriptions of the 470T “Fulgur” (2 copies). (Item 15)
      - Description of the 462 B4. (Item 16)
      - Specifications for the 460 M5. (Item 17)
      - Blueprints for the “Super TR.” (Item 18)
      - “Note Descriptive” for the Breguet 392T. (Item 19)
      - Folder describing the Breguet 41. (Item 20)
      - Diagram of an unidentified aircraft. (Item 21)
      - Illustration of the Breguet 470T. (Item 22)
      - Description and specifications for the “Bizerte.” (Item 23)
      - Description and specifications for the Breguet 27. (Item 24)
      - Brochure and diagram showing dimensions for the Breguet 470T “Fulgur.” (Item 25)
    - Bronzavia. (Envelope 14)
      - Photograph of a Bronzavia radio. (Item 1)
      - Description of the M 535 and M 500 radios. (Item 2)
      - Catalogue of equipment produced by Bronzavia. (Item 3)
      - Catalogue of equipment produced by Bronzavia. (Item 4)
  - Burnelli, Campbell, Caudron-Renault, Cellon, Centre d'Aviation Populaire, Centre d'Information du Nickel, Centro Studi et Esperience per il Volo a Vela, Cessna, Chamoy Chantiers, Le Chimiste, Compteurs Montrouge, Concorde, Consolidated Aircraft, Consolidated Vultee, Controleur ACDFK Corben. (Box 25)
    - Burnelli Aircraft Ltd. (Envelope 1)
      - Blueprints for the Model 14A. (Item 1)
      - Graphs depicting drag and other variables. (Item 2)
      - Letter to l’Aérophile, 1936. (Item 3)
      - Descriptions (French) of Burnelli Aircraft. (Item 4)
    - Campbell Aircraft Company. (Envelope 2)
      - Letter to l’Aérophile with enclosed photograph and description of their new “Ford V8 powered airplane.” (Item 1)
    - Caudron-Renault. (Envelope 3)
      - Letter to l’Aérophile with an accompanying comparison of the C.690 and C.720. (Item 1)
      - “Influence de la Coupe Deustch sur la Construction Aeronautique.” (Item 2)
      - Letter from R. Giraud, Directeur des Services de Publicité. (Item 3)
      - “L’Activite de ‘Caudron-Renault’ de 1936 à 1938” from the “Salon de l’Aeronautique 1938.” (Item 4)
      - Letter from Pierre Garnier to the “Bulletin de la Navigation Aerienne.” (Item 5)
      - “Documentation Sur L’Activite de la Societe Caudron-Renault de 1934 à 1936” from the “Salon de l’Aeronautique 1936.” (Item 6)
      - Description and specifications for the Caudron-Renault “Cyclone.” (Item 7)
      - Description and specifications for the Caudron C.278 135. (Item 8)
      - Specifications for the Avion Caudron C.274. (Item 9)
      - Specifications for the PV.200. (Item 10)
      - Specifications for the Caudron C.274. (Item 11)
      - Three diagrams of airplane dimensions including the P.V 200. (Item 12)
      - Brochure containing specifications for Caudron Renault aircraft and the slogan “plus de 33 fois le tour de la terre” (more than thirty-three times around the Earth). (Item 13)
      - Brochure for the Caudron-Renault “Simoun.” (Item 14)
      - Brochure (in French and English) for the Caudron-Renault Goéland.” (Item 15)
      - Description and specifications for the C.270 “Luciole.” (Item 16)
      - Description and specifications for the C.232. (Item 17)
      - Blueprint of the C.232. (Item 18)
      - Blueprints for the C432. (Item 19)
      - Blueprints for the “Velodyne No. 1.” (Item 20)
      - Diagram showing the dimensions of the “Hangar C.G” for the “Avion Caudron C-282.” (Item 21)
      - Blueprints for the C-480. (Item 22)
      - Diagram showing the dimensions for the “Caudron Super Phaléne.” (Item 23)
      - Blueprints for the C-286V. (Item 24)
      - Diagram showing the dimensions of the Amphibie Caudron PV 200. (Item 25)
      - Blueprints for the C-286V. (Item 26)
      - Blueprints for the C-520. (Item 27)
      - Blueprints for the Caudron C-272 “Moteur Renault 95 C.V.” (Item 28)
      - Blueprints for the C-510. (Item 29)
      - Blueprints for the C-278. (Item 30)
      - Blueprints for the “Amphibie Caudron.” (Item 31)
      - Blueprints for the C-460 “Coup Deutsch 1934.” (Item 32)
    - Cellon Ltd. (Envelope 4)
      - Cellon Aircraft Finishes catalog with two pamphlets pertaining to finishes for wood and metal. Two display samples (the finish on metal) are also included. (Item 1)
    - Centre d’Aviation Populaire de la Region Nazairienne. (Envelope 5)
      - Dossier pertaining to the SCA 10, including blueprints, diagrams, specifications and a detailed description. (Item 1)
    - Centre d’Information du Nickel. (Envelope 6)
      - Pamphlet on the processing of nickel and non-ferrous alloys (Item 1)
      - Report “L’Industrie du Nickel” written by R.C Stanley, president of the “L’International Nickel Company of Canada Ltd.” (Item 2)
    - Centro Studi ed Esperience Per il Volo a Vela. (Envelope 7)
      - Diagram of “ferrures d'attache des ailes” (attachment fitting of wings). (Item 1)
      - Diagram of “boulon conique” (conical bolt). (Item 2)
      - Graph (in Italian) “Glide Ratio as a Function of Speed.” (Item 3)
      - Graph (in Italian) “Speed of Descent in Terms of Speed Horizontal.” (Item 4)
      - Unidentified blueprint of an Italian aircraft. (Item 5)
    - Cessna Aircraft Company. (Envelope 8)
      - Article “The New Cessna Airmaster Climaxes 27 Years of Progressive Engineering” in the “Cessna Times,”, 1938., (2 copies). (Item 1)
      - Advertising pamphlet “‘The World’s Most Efficient Airplane.’” (Item 2)
      - Advertisement “The 1939 Cessna Airmaster.” (Item 3)
      - Advertising pamphlet “The New Cessna C-38 Airmaster.” (Item 4)
      - Report on the Cessna “Airmaster 1939.” (Item 5)
    - Chamoy. (Envelope 9)
      - Blueprints for the FC2 (three articles). (Item 1)
    - Chantiers Aeronautiques Wibault Pennoet. (Envelope 10)
      - Letter mentioning the recent issue of “Aircraft Engineering” that featured the Wibault-Penhoët Type 282 T12. (Item 1)
      - Documentary note on the devices Chantiers submitted to an air show in 1932. (Item 2)
      - Clipping “Le géant que nous construisons pourra transporter 26 passagers, en 48 heures, de Paris à Saïgon,”, 1937. (Item 3)
      - Two pamphlets with statistics for the Wibault-Penhoët 360 T.5, (2 copies) (Item 4)
    - La Chimiste. (Envelope 11)
      - Advertisement and detailed description (including a report by the Office National Des Recherches Scientifiques Et Industrielles & Des Inventions) of an extinguisher to be used against attacks by incendiary bombs “Le Chimiste,”, 1937. (Item 1)
    - Compteurs Mantrouge. (Envelope 12)
      - Article “Vibrograph” in “Comptreurs Montrouge”, (2 copies). (Item 1)
      - Article “Oscillographie Cathodique Portatif C.d.C. Type OCP 21.” (Item 2)
    - Concorde. (Envelope 13)
      - Press release “Concorde Lands In The United States.” (Item 1)
      - Press release “United States Companies Working on Concorde”, 1973. (Item 2)
      - Press release “Airline Pilots Praise Concorde SST.” (Item 3)
      - Press report “Concorde Background Brief,”, 1972. (Item 4)
    - Consolidated Aircraft Corporations. (Envelope 14)
      - “Detail Specification for Consolidated Attack Type Airplanes,”, 1935. (Item 1)
      - Press release “Consolidated Bomber Undergoes Tests,”, 1940. (Item 2)
      - Press release for the Model 32 bomber. (Item 3)
      - Consolidated Aircraft “The FLEET Trainer.” (Item 4)
      - Letter to l’Aérophile from Consolidated Aircraft Corporation, 1936. (Item 5)
      - Specifications for Fleet airplanes (subsidiary of Consolidated Aircraft) including Models 5, 10 and 11. (Item 6)
      - “Consolidated Specification Covering Consolidated Model 21M General Purpose Airplane with Pratt & Whitney R-985-SB Aircooled Engine.” (Item 7)
      - “Detail Specification for Consolidated “Ranger” Twin-Engine Flying Boat.” (Item 8)
      - “Consolidated Specification Covering Consolidated PT-11 Training Airplane with Wright R-760-E Aircooled Engine.” (Item 9)
      - Consolidated Aircraft company magazine, first issue, September 1936. (Item 10)
    - Consolidated Vultee Corp. (Envelope 15)
      - Photograph of the Liberator B-24 bomber. (Item 1)
      - Specifications for the Liberator B-24. (Item 2)
    - Controleur ACDFK. (Envelope 16)
      - Instillation and use handbook for the “Tableau De Pilotage Badin Type 40.” (Item 1)
      - Instillation and use handbook for the “Supports Élastiques Badin.” (Item 2)
      - Instillation and use handbook for the “Contrôleur E.G Sperry-Badin Type 10.” (Item 3)
      - Instillation and use handbook for the “Conservateur de Cap Sperry-Badin Type 10.” (Item 4)
      - Blueprints for A-60T and A-71T. (Item 5)
      - Letter to l’Aérophile, October 1936. (Item 6)
      - Report “L’Appareillage Aéronautique” containing eight detailed diagrams of aeronautical equipment. (Item 7)
    - Corben Aircraft. (Envelope 17)
      - Corben Aircraft catalog with price sheet, 1935. (Item 1)
  - Cunliffe-Owen, Curtiss-Wright, Reichsverband der Deutschen Luftafahrt Industrie, Devoitine, Dispostif Cinematique Perfetti, Douglas, Electric Auto-liter, L'Epopee Aerienne, Fairchild. (Box 26)
    - Cunliffe-Owen Aircraft Ltd. (Envelope 1)
      - “Preliminary Specification for the Supply of General Purpose Transport Aircraft.” The Cunliffe-Owen “Flying Wing” O.A Mark 2. (Item 1)
    - Curtiss-Wright. (Envelope 2)
      - Article reprinted from Aviation “The ‘Tell Tale’ Instrument Panel of the New 36-Passenger Curtiss-Wright CW-20 Transport.” (Item 1)
      - Press release and attached photograph of the new “sweep back” propeller. (Item 2)
      - Press release and attached photograph of the Army Air Force “gas turbine engine laboratory.” (Item 3)
    - Curtiss-Wright Corporation. (Envelope 3)
      - Press release “New American Substratosphere Transport Nearing Completion,” December 1939. (Item 1)
      - Specifications for the Curtiss Type III Hawk Fighter. (Item 2)
      - Press release “First of Large of Order of New Curtiss Advanced Combat Trainers Passes Final Flight Tests,”, December 1939. (Item 3)
      - Five letters from the Curtiss-Wright Corporation to l’Aérophile. (Item 4)
      - Specifications for the 16E Primary Trainer and the “Condor BT-32 Bomber, Transport Ambulance and Photographic Plane.” (Item 5)
      - Seven hand-drawn sketches of Curtiss aircraft including the SDC-1, BFC-2, Hawk III, Hawk IV, XSBC-3, YLA-18 and the Strike. (Item 6)
      - Three letters to l’Aérophile, 1936. (Item 7)
      - Report on the Curtiss-Wright Model 19R. (Item 8)
      - Press release “New Stall-Proof, Spin-Proof Airplane Competed For the Bureau of Air Commerce,” 1936. (Item 9)
      - Specifications for the Curtiss “Strike.” (Item 10)
      - Press release “New Curtiss-Wright Amphibion [sic] With Many Novel Features Takes the Air.” (Item 11)
      - Specifications for the “Curtiss Type IV Single Seat Hawk Fighter.” (Item 12)
      - Article reprinted from Aero Digest “Curtiss-Wright CW-21,”, February 1939. (Item 13)
      - Press release and attached photograph of a graph depicting the record-breaking Curtiss pursuit plane. (Item 14)
      - Letter to l’Aérophile with description of the Curtiss-Wright Osprey C14R. (Item 15)
      - Pamphlet “Curtiss-Wright Advanced Military Trainer.” (Item 16)
      - Performance characteristics for the Cyclone “F” Series, Conqueror “F” Series and Whirlwind “E” Series. (Item 17)
      - Press release and seven enclosed photographs “1000 Men Engaged in Construction of New 30-Passenger Curtiss-Wright Transport at St. Louis Airplane Division,”, 1938. (Item 18)
      - Advertising pamphlet for the “The Curtiss-Wright Condor” describing the aircraft as a “Luxury Liner of the Air.” The pamphlet compares the sound of the aircraft to a Pullman car. (Item 19)
      - Report on the Curtiss-Wright Model 19R. (Item 20)
      - Description and characteristics of the “Transport De Troupes Americaines.” (Item 21)
      - Curtiss-Wright Trainer. (Item 22)
    - Der Reichsverband der Deutschen Luftfahrt-Industrie. (Envelope 4)
      - Publication “Der Reichsverband der Deutschen Luftfahrt-Industrie” detailing the proceedings (with photographs) of an exhibition in Belgrade, 1938. (Item 1)
    - Devoitine. (Envelope 5)
      - Specifications sent to l’Aérophile for Devoitine airplanes including the D.520S, 1943. (Item 1)
      - Blueprints and diagram of the D.520. (Item 2)
      - Specification for the D.43. (Item 3)
      - Characteristics of the 510. (Item 4)
      - Letter to L’Aérophile, 1936. (Item 5)
      - Characteristics of Devoitine aircraft. (Item 6)
      - Eight publications with characteristics and photographs of Devoitine aircraft including the D.332, D.333, D.338, D.500 and the D.430 Colonial. (Item 7)
    - Le Dispositif Cinematique Perfetti. (Envelope 6)
      - Publication: Moteurs A Barillet “Le Dispositif Cinematique Perfetti.” (Item 1)
    - Douglas Motors Ltd. (Envelope 7)
      - Blueprint graph showing R.P.M and B.H.P. (Item 1)
    - Douglas Aircraft Company, Inc. (Envelope 8)
      - Press release “Douglas Receives CAA Certificates.” (Item 1)
      - Press release “Douglas Announces New Service, Parts Program”., (2 copies). (Item 2)
      - Press release: DC-3C “Exectutive” transport., (3 folders) (Item 3)
    - Douglas Aircraft Corporation. (Envelope 9)
      - Advertising brochure for the Douglas Super Transport, DC-3 DST. (Item 1)
      - Advertising brochure: United Air Lines “presents the Mainliner” the “Ultimate in Air Travel Luxury.” The advertisement notes that “Bridge players prefer United’s Skylounge, which permits passengers to swivel into position around a standard-size card table.” (Item 2)
      - Model plan and specifications for the DC-3. (Item 3)
      - Press release introducing the DC-4. (Item 4)
      - Press release and attached advertisement for the Douglas Sleeper Transport (DST). The advertisement compares the DST to the Pullman Car. (Item 5)
      - Detailed report of the DC-5 with photographs, brochures, specifications and blueprints. (Item 6)
    - Electric Auto-Lite Company. (Envelope 10)
      - Press release and four attached photographs and diagrams introducing the new Sterling Steelductor, 1939. (Item 1)